A Guide to the Papers of William Faulkner, 1824-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of William Faulkner, 1824-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8425 -b
This collection consists of ca. 120 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of Linton Massey on 14 August 1967.
Scope and Content Information
The bulk of the papers consist of Falkner [sic] family papers, 1824-1964, the Mississippi ancestors of William Faulkner. These include bills receipts, indentures and certificates of election of John Wesley Thompson Falkner, William C. Falkner, and John Wesley Thompson. Of interest are a number of receipts for the sale of slaves.
Contents List
- "A Nosegay" by Justiania Word, Jr., 1 p. on 1 l. 1824 May 1, AMsS
- John Wesley Thompson to Justiania D. Thompson, 4 p. on 2 l. 1834 August 20, ALS
- John Wesley Thompson to Justiania D. Thompson, 2 p. on 1 l. 1834 September 20, ALS
- Justiania Thompson to John Wesley Thompson, and his reply, 3 p. on 1 l. 1834 October 12, ALS
- Indictment of John W. Thompson et al for (copied 1835 October 31) murder, with notation of the innocence, 1834 October, 3 p. on 2 l. ADS
- Beginning "Jehovah Jove.. ." by William Adams [1839?] June 29, 2 p. on 1 l. AMs
  poem
- Certificate of John Wesley Thompson's election as District Attorney, 1 p. 1841 November 13, ADS
- Receipts for state, county, and federal taxes 1846-1868, 18 items. Receipts
- A. Biggs to John Wesley Thompson 1849 July 27, 1 p. on 1 l. Receipt
- F. T. Leak to John W. Thompson 1852 January, 1 p. on 1 l. Receipt for the sale of "Emily a mulatto girl slave."
- Legal notice by William C. Falkner, Presidential Election of 1884, & miscellaneous items 1855-1884, 6 items. Newspaper clippings
- Receipts for state, county taxes for William M. Prince 1856-1858, 3 items. Receipts
- Sirene S. Sweeten to John W. Thompson for payment for a slave 1857 January 7, 1 p. on 1 l. Receipt
- James B. Ellis to John W. Thompson, slave receipt 1857 March 15, 1 p. on 1 l. Receipt
- William C. Falkner to John W. Thompson, for a slave 1857 March 21, 1 p. on 1 l. Receipt
- John W. Thompson's shareholders certificate in Book and Tract Society 1859 July 13, 1 p. on 1 l. ADS
- G. W. Humphrey to M. Carpenter 1869 March 30, 1 p. on 1 l. ANS
- Indenture between G. M. Maddox and John W. Thompson 1871 July 18, 4 p. on 1 l. ADS
- Agreement between William C. Falkner and John W. T. Falkner 1872 December 6, 4 p. on 1 l. ADS
- Agreement between John Thompson and John W. T. Falkner 1873 February 6, 3 p. on 1 l. ADS
- Agreement between John W. Thompson and Justiania Thompson and John W. T. Falkner 1873 February 6, 4 p. on 1 l. ADS
- Notes on John Wesley Thompson's birth and death dates; business card of Thompson & Falkner [1873?], Notes
- Chiefly canceled checks drawn by J. W. T. Falkner or Hall & Falkner, and envelope bearing notation regarding bonds 1873-1920, 19 items. Checks, etc.
- J. A. Williams [?] to J. M. Phipps covering a copy of a land patent 1880 May 27, 1 p. on 1 l. LS
- $100 note of W. A. Crum to Dillard & Coffin 1880 October 2, 2 p. on 1 l. ANS
- Agreement between W. C. Falkner and W. L. Nugent and J. S. Hamilton 1889 July 2, 3 p. on 2 l. ADS(copy)
- Agreement between John W. T. Falkner for W. C. Falkner with W. L. Nugent and J. S. Hamilton 1889 July 2, 3 p. on 2 l. AD(copy)
- W. M. Stone General Land Office to Howry & Falkner 1889 September 14, 1 p. on 1 l. ALS
- Lewis A. Groff, General Land Office to Howry & Falkner 1889 October 12, 1 p. on 1 l. LS
- "Letters Testamentary" for the Estate of William C. Falkner 1889 November, 2 p. ADS
- William C. Falkner with Nicholas Williams & Co. 1889, 4 p. on 4 l. Accounts
- John W. T. Falkner's election as state legislator 1891 December 1, 1 p. on 1 l. Certificate
- John W. T. Falkner's election as state senator 1895 November 7, 1 p. on 1 l. Certificate
- John W. T. Falkner's election as state senator 1895 November 15, 1 p. on 1 l. Certificate
- John W. T. Falkner's appointment as a Trustee of the University of Mississippi 1896 March 25, 1 p. on 1 l. Certificate
- Letter of appointment of John W. T. Falkner from Judson Hormon 1896 June 16, 2 p. on 1 l. TLS
- Regarding extension of the Gulf and Chicago Railroad 1897, 4 items. Miscellaneous
- Receipt to J. W. T. Falkner as Attorney for the University of Mississippi 1898 June 24, 1 p. on 1 l. Receipt
- J. W. T. Falkner's election as state senator 1899 November 20, 1 p. on 1 l. Certificate
- Receipt to J. W. T. Falkner, Attorney for the University of Mississippi 1899 December 27, 1 p. on 1 l. Receipt
- Miscellaneous notes of [J. W. T. Thompson?] 189[?], 4 p. on 2 l. Notes
- J. W. T. Falkner's 10th Annual Report as Executor of Col. William C. Falkner 1900 May, 6 p. on 6 l. Typescript
- J. W. T. Falkner's appointment as a Delegate to the Southern Industrial Convention 1900 October 24, 1 p. on 1 l. Certificate
- J. W. T. Falkner's 11th Annual Report as Executor of Col. William C. Falkner 1901 May, 7 p. on 6 l. Typescript
- J. W. T. Falkner's election as an Alderman of the town of Oxford, Mississippi 1902 March 2, 1 p. on 1 l. Certificate
- Claim against estate of T. E. Harris by Mrs. L. Yates; attached note for $500 1906 May 29, 2 items. Legal Papers
- Bank statements and canceled checks of J. W. T. Falkner 1915-1916, 19 items. Bank statements & checks
- Assignment of an insurance policy to J. W. T. Falkner 1916, 3 items. Insurance policy
- "Assessments of Solvent Credits, Money on Hand, on Deposit or Loaned as Shown by the Records," for J. W. T. Falkner 1917 December 28, 1 p. on 1 l. Document
- Receipt for machinery purchased from Patton & Taylor 1920 May 19, 1 p. on 1 l. Receipt
- Sallie Burus to Sallie Murry, enclosing notes on the "Falkner-Thurmond Affair," 1964 January 23, 4 p. on 2 l. ALS
- Regarding debts due J. W. T. Falkner n. d., 2 p. on 1 l. Notes
- 2 poems by [J. W. Thompson?] n. d., 4 p. on 2 l. AMs
- William C. Falkner, Novelist, from publications of the Mississippi Historical Society, by A. L. Bondurant; inscribed by author, with envelope addressed to Mrs. R. X. Williams from S. F. Burus, 1964 May 2. n. d., 15 p. on 8 l. Reprint